Guide to the Helen and Newton Harrison Papers M1797
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Project Files, 1969-2011
  - Subseries 13. Horton Plaza, 1977-1978
    - Horton Plaza; Reports, Horton Plaza Redevelopment Project: Balboa Theater Feasibility Report, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
      by Architects Munroe and Reeves AIA
    - Horton Plaza; Reports, Preliminary Draft Environmental Impact Report: Horton Plaza Redevelopment Project, City of San Diego - June 17, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Horton Plaza; Reports, Proposal to Prepare an Environmental Impact Report for the Horton Plaza Redevelopment Project, City of San Diego - June 17, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Horton Plaza; Reports, Response to Draft EIR (Environmental Impact Report) for Centre City Development, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 14. Sacramento Meditations, 1977
    This subseries consists of correspondence, project descriptions, exhibition information, maps, photographic material, posters, planning, notes, research, and text. The nine texts of the Sacramento Meditations are the revised version of the work commissioned by the Floating Museum (1976) and exhibited by the San Francisco Museum of Art (1977). This project examines water use practices in California. It includes eleven posters each beginning with “For instance…if…” and ending with “What if all irrigated farming isn’t necessary?” These were posted by the Harrisons, San Francisco Art Institute students, and others on street corners throughout San Francisco, as well as billboards saying “Water”; street graffiti written with chalk on the sidewalks; video, radio and TV spots; and other performances. Another name used for this project is “Meditations on the Sacramento River, the Delta, and the Bays at San Francisco.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Sacramento Meditations; The Campaign, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Sacramento Meditations; The Campaign, Notes, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Correspondence, 1976-1977, 1998 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Correspondence, undated (Flat-box 272, Folder 12)
      Outgoing to Lynn Hershman
    - Sacramento Meditations; Descriptions, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Exhibitions, From the Lagoon Cycle: From the Meditations, Emanuel Walter Gallery, San Francisco Art Institute, San Francisco, CA, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Exhibitions, Meditations on the Condition of the Sacramento River, the Delta and the Bays of San Francisco, 1977 (Map-folder 416)
      For exhibitions at the Floating Museum, San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, and San Francisco Art Institute.
    - Sacramento Meditations; Exhibitions, Meditation on the Condition of the Sacramento River, Its Delta and the Bays of San Francisco, San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, San Francisco, CA, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Exhibitions, Unidentified, undated (Flat-box 272, Folder 13)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Floating Museum, 1975-1977 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Map, undated (Map-folder 318)
      Handmade out of tissue paper.
    - Sacramento Meditations; Maps, 1959, 1967-1970 (Map-folder 319)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Maps, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Maps, 1972-1975 (Map-folder 319)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Meditations on the Condition of the Sacramento River Delta: An Icon for Transformation [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 260, Folder 7)
      by Suzanne Buettgar for Art History 181
    - Sacramento Meditations; "One Full Work and Part of Another" (by Helen Mayer Harrison / Newton Harrison in New Wilderness Letter, Vol. 1, Nos. 3-4, Dec. 1977 / Jan. 1978, 1977-1978 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Packet, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      Text and bibliography
    - Sacramento Meditations; Performances, The House That Jack Built, Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago, IL, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Photographic materials, Contact sheets, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Photographic materials, Negatives, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Photographic materials, Photographs, 1977, undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Photographic materials, Transparencies, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Planning and notes, 1977 (Box 42, Folders 16-17, Box 43, Folders 1-3)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Posters, 1977 (Flat-box 272, Folders 14-15)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Posters (Photocopies), 1977 (Flat-boxes 273, Folder 1)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Press, 1977-1978 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, Bibliography, 1977, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, Agriculture, 1970-1977 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, General, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, General, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, Geology, 1972-1974, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, Water, 1969-1974, undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, Water, 1974-1975 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, Water, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, Water, 1976-1979 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, California, Water recreation, 1973-1977 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Research, General research / information, 1971-1977, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Text, "For instance ... if" posters, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Text, Graffiti Lists, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Text, Meditations on the Condition of the Watershed of the Sacramento / San Joaquin Rivers and the Central Valley of California, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Text, Public service TV spots and ads in the personal columns, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Text, Sacramento Meditations, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Text, Sacramento Meditations (Draft), 1977 (Flat-box 268, Folder 10)
    - Sacramento Meditations; Text, Sacramento Meditations (Meditation on the Condition of the Sacramento River, the Delta and the Bays at San Francisco), 1977 (Box 45, Folder 9, Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 15. Baltimore Promenade, 1981
    This subseries consists of contact information, correspondence, project descriptions, exhibition information, maps, photographic material, planning, notes, press, proposals, publicity, research, a scrapbook, and text. This work was initiated by the Maryland Institute and supported by the National Endowment for the Arts, various city and civic agencies, and the office of the then mayor of Baltimore. The Harrisons were originally invited to comment on the problematic design of inner city housing, but once in Baltimore, they perceived the city to be divided. The Harrisons proposed reconnecting the city by creating north-south and east-west promenades that intersected at the city’s harbor. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Baltimore Promenade; Brochure, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Brochures, 1981 (Map-folder 417)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Contact information, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Contact information, undated (Flat-box 268, Folder 11)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Descriptions, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Exhibitions, The Maryland Institute, College of Art, Decker Gallery, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Exhibitions, Unidentified installations, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Grants, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Map, 1975 (Flat-box 268, Folder 12)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Maps, 1974-1979, undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Maps, 1979-1982 (Map-folder 321)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Maps, 1981, undated (Map-folder 418)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Notes, undated (Flat-box 268, Folder 13)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Packets, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Photographic material, Photographs, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Photographic material, Photographs, 1981 (Flat-box 268, Folder 14)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Planning and notes, undated (Box 46, Folders 12-13)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Press, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Proposals, 1981, undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Reference book 2, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Arts and entertainment, 1976, 1980-1982 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Arts and entertainment, 1980-1981, undated (Map-folder 419)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Arts and entertainment, undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Arts and entertainment, undated (Flat-box 268, Folder 15)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Baltimore harbor, 1981, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Baltimore Scene Magazine, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Boston, 1974-1976, undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Misc., 1981, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Neighborhoods, people, and history, 1978-1979 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Neighborhoods, people, and history, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Neighborhoods, people, and history, 1981, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Philadelphia, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Questionnaires, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Questionnaire tally, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Questionnaire tally, 1981 (Flat-box 269, Folder 2)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Redevelopment, 1980 (Flat-box 269, Folder 1)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Research, Redevelopment, 1981, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Scrapbook, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Scrapbook, undated (Flat-box 289)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, Eastern Avenue, undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, From the Perspective of Jones Falls, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, The Harbor, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, Howard Street, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, Mount Royal Center, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, Patterson Park, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, Performances, undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, Unidentified, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Baltimore Promenade; Text, WBAL radio commercial, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 16. Barrier Islands Drama, 1982-1983
    This subseries consists of contact information, project descriptions, exhibition information, photographic material, planning, notes, press, research, maps, and text. Commissioned by the Ringling Museum in Sarasota, Florida, for the exhibition Five Artists on the Florida Landscape, this project examined the impact of the nonnative Casuarinas (a pine-like tree native to Australia) that was introduced to the area for landscaping purposes. The full title is “Barrier Island Drama - The Mangrove and the Pine.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Contact information, 1980, undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Descriptions, undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Exhibitions, Barrier Islands Drama: The Mangrove and the Pine, Wenger Gallery, La Jolla, CA, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Exhibitions, Common Ground: Five Artists in the Florida Landscape, Ringling Museum, Sarasota, FL, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Exhibitions, Installation, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Exhibitions, Floorplan, undated (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Exhibitions, Maps, undated (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Maps, 1974 (Flat-box 269, Folder 3)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Maps, 1976, undated (Map-folder 322)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Maps, 1977, 1982 (Map-folder 420)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Photographic material, Photographs, undated (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Photographic material, Photographs (Copies), undated (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Planning and notes, undated (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Press, 1982, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Barrier Islands, Cayo-Costa Island, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Barrier Islands, General, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Barrier Islands, North Captiva Island, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Barrier Islands, Sanibel Island, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida, 1971 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida, 1975, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida, undated (Map-folder 421)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Florida postcards, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Hurricanes, 1980-1981 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Mining and drilling for phosphate and oil, 1978, 1980, undated (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Misc. information about Florida, 1979-1980, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Plants and vegetation, 1963, 1973, 1977, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Sarasota and Sarasota County, FL, 1975, 1977-1979, 1981, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Seminole Indians, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Research, Wildlife, 1974, 1979, 1981, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Barrier Islands Drama; Text, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 17. Fortress Atlanta, 1982-1983
    This subseries consists of correspondence, project descriptions, exhibition information, maps, photographic material, planning, notes, research, maps, and text. The Harrisons were invited to Atlanta by the Emory University Art Gallery to do a work for the gallery’s annual conference. The conference theme that year was human rights. The Harrisons took up the issue of architecture and human rights. This work, through images and text, presented the ways in which architects and planners interfered with the rights (and rites) of assembly and passage on the streets. The full name of this project is “Fortress Atlanta: Rites of Assembly and Rights of Passage.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Fortress Atlanta; Biographical information about Helen and Newton Harrison, undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Descriptions, undated (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Exhibitions, Fortress Atlanta: On Rites of Assembly and Rights of Passage, Emory University Symposium "Rethinking Human Rights", 1983 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Flyer for seminar by Kasper König, Germany, 1986 (Flat-box 269, Folder 4)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Maps, 1973, 1981-1982 (Map-folder 422)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Maps, 1981-1982, undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Newspapers, Local, 1982 (Flat-box 273, Folder 1982)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Photographic Material, Photographs, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Planning and notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Research, 1975, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Fortress Atlanta; Text, undated (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Fortress Atlanta; University of Georgia, Department of Art, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 18. Guadalupe Meander, 1982-1983
    This subseries consists of contact information, correspondence, project descriptions, exhibition information, maps, photographic material, planning, notes, press, proposals, research, National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) grant material, and text. Supported by the Art Gallery of San Jose State University and later funded by the Arts Council of the City of San Jose, the work, an elaborate mural, proposed the reclamation of the Guadalupe River in San Jose, California. The full title of the project is “The Guadalupe Meander, a Refugia for San Jose.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Guadalupe Meander; Contact information, undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Correspondence, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Descriptions, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Exemption request, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Financial, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Guadalupe River Park Task Force, 1982-1984 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Exhibitions, undated (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Map, undated (Flat-box 269, Folder 5)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Maps, 1981, undated (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Maps, 1982, undated (Map-folder 423)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Maps, 1985, undated (Map-folder 323)
    - Guadalupe Meander; NEA grant information, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Photographic material, Content Inventory, undated (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Photographic material, Photographs, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Photographic material, Photographs, 1983 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Photographic material, Photographs (Copies), undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Photographic material, Photographs, undated (Map-folder 324)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Photographic material, Photographs, undated (Map-folder 424)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Planning and notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Press, 1983 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Proposals, 1983, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Archaeological, 1981, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Arts and entertainment, 1983, undated (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Bibliography, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Economic, 1982 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Environment, 1974, 1987, undated (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Guadalupe River, 1971, 1978, undated (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Parks, Guadalupe River Park, 1971, 1983, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Parks, Guadalupe River Park, 1985 (Flat-box 269, Folder 6)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Parks, Santa Clara County, 1978, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Plants and animals, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Santa Clara County, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Santa Clara County, 1983 (Flat-box 269, Folder 7)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Water in Santa Clara Valley, 1977-1978, 1981-1983 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Research, Water in Santa Clara County, undated (Flat-box 269, Folder 8)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Text, 1983, undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Guadalupe Meander; Text, undated (Flat-box 269, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 19. A Grand Round for San Diego, 1983-1986
    This subseries consists of budgets, correspondence, project descriptions, planning, notes, photographic material, press, and text. Created for an architectural conference that addressed the issues of new amenities for San Diego, it imagined a grand canal that operated as both an “urban fantasy” and as a flood control measure. The full title of this work is “A Grand Round for San Diego, 1985: On Foot, Across the Water, Through the Air.” The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Budgets, 1983-1986 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Descriptions, 1983-1986 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Photographic material, Photograph, 1986 (Flat-box 273, Folder 3)
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Planning and notes, 1978 (Flat-box 273, Folder 4)
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Planning and notes, 1983-1986 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Press, 1985-1986 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - A Grand Round for San Diego; Text, 1983-1986 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 20. Santa Barbara Sites, 1985-1988
    This subseries consists of artist information, contracts and agreements, correspondence, schedules, publicity, photographic material, a map, National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) grant material, and research. For this project, the Santa Barbara Sites project team, led by the Harrisons, was tasked with developing public art projects for six sites in and around Santa Barbara, California. The project was supported by the Community School, Inc. and the City of Santa Barbara’s Visual Art in Public Places Subcommittee of the Arts Advisory Committee. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Artist Team, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Contracts and agreements, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Harrison visit schedule, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Invoice, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Lectures, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Map, 1981 (Map-folder 425)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; NEA Design Arts grant application, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Photographic material, Negatives, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Photographic material, Photographs, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Planning and notes, 1986-1989 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Possible Committee Members, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Proposed sites and selected sites, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Research, 1984, 1986, undated (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Santa Barbara Sites; Sponsors, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 21. Pasadena, 1969-1998
    This subseries consists of contracts and agreements, correspondence, project descriptions, exhibition information, meeting documentation, printed material, financial records, research, reports, photographic material, press, maps, National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) grant material, posters, drawings, and text documenting three projects of the Harrisons’ at the Devil’s Gate Dam in Pasadena, California: “Arroyo Seco Release: A Proposal for Pasadena” (1985), “Devil’s Gate: A Refuge for Pasadena” (1987), and “From the Air: A String of Emeralds” (1991).